LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode

Ahmedabad, India Email: deeppatel7521@gmail.com | Mobile: (+91) 8347209963

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

I am a highly skilled full stack developer with over **3 years of experience** in .NET CORE, Azure, MS SQL, Angular, Microservices, GitHub. Worked with the business and client stakeholders to understand the underlying technologies and systems; conduct a system analysis by reviewing the criticality of modules.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : C# | .NET | JavaScript | TypeScript | C++ | Java | HTML5 | CSS | Bootstrap | jQuery | Git

Frameworks : .NET CORE WEB API | Entity Core | MVC | Angular 8+ | Knockout.js | NUnit | Docker

Cloud : Azure DevOps | CI/CD | App Service | Container Service | CosmosDB | Azure Functions | ACI | AKS

**Databases** : MSSQL | MongoDB | PostgreSQL

Dev Tools : Visual Studio | VS Code | Git | Postman | SSMS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer(FullStack)

Cognizant Technology Solutions

July 2020 – Present Pune, India

- Led the design and development of multiple screens using Angular, Azure, .NET CORE, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
   MSSQL, etc. also delivering user-friendly interface and enhanced user experiences.
- Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from databases
- Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipelines using DevOps practices, Deployment process, Pull Requests, Code Reviews, Unit Testing.
- Implemented new Stored Procedure, Tables, Synonyms.
- Applied test-driven development methodologies to write clean, maintainable, and high-quality code, resulting in reduced defects and improved codebase stability.
- Integrated third-party APIs and libraries- to extend application functionality, enhancing the overall user experience.
- Improved website performance and speed through optimization in codebase.
- Troubleshot and fixed bugs and issues in the backend to ensure smooth operation of the applications
- Actively participated in Agile ceremonies, including sprint planning, daily stand-ups, sprint reviews, and retrospectives, to ensure timely delivery of software features.

### Jr. Software Intern

Feb 2020 – July 2020 Bangalore, India

Cognizant Technology Solutions

Worked on implementing a web application to perform all CRUD operations following Fault tolerant Microservices
 Architecture.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Institute Of Technology, Nirma University**

B.Tech in Instrumentation and Control (Minor in Computer Science) | CGPA: 8.19

Ahmedabad, Gujarat Aug. 2016 – May. 2020

### **PROJECTS**

# Tweet App

### Angular, Azure, C#, ASP.NET CORE WEB API, Git

Source Code

- Implemented the **Microservices** to Process the Tweet for CRUD operations.
- Deployed Frontend and Backend on Azure via Azure App Service, Azure Container Instances

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- · Accredited as ADM Junior Engineer FSE1 Digital Honors Program in Oct'22.
- Awarded Digital Badge for completing the ADM BootUp Warrior Foundation Program in July'21.
- Secured GOLD CUP in National Automation Competition MECUP 2020